okay number four asks which of the
following is the strongest base that
means that we're looking at the ability
of these compounds to accept a proton in
all of these cases we're looking at some
lone pairs on oxygen and nitrogen so
this oxygen has two lone pairs this
oxygen has two lone pairs this nitrogen
has one lone pair and this nitrogen has
one lone pair in each case an acid base
reaction is going to occur whereby
either oxygen or nitrogen is accepting a
proton with a lone pair and so which is
able to do it best now what we have to
understand is that these lone pairs are
not all equally available for acid base
reactions some of them are tied up in
resonance so for example over here on
this phol we've got a lone pair that can
get pushed down here and then all of
this Pi electron density can be
delocalized we have a lot of different
res